Guide to the General Photograph Collection: Portraits MSS.PHOTO.0100
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- M.A. Banahan (now Brady) 1862 [Sewell's photograph, Sonora], circa 1863 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Sonora (Calif.); Columbia (Calif.); Banahan, Margaret Agnes, 1849-1925
- Harry Elmer Barnes [photograph and clipping] (Box 11, Folder 15)
  Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1889-1968
- P.T. Barnum & Commodore Nutt [Charles D. Fredricks photograph, New York] (Box 11, Folder 16)
  Barnum, P.T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Morrison, George Washington, 1809-1888
- Henry N. [Bary? Gary?] [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to "Sam" 1920] (Box 11, Folder 17)
- A.C. Bassett, Southern Pacific Railroad [Thompson & Co. photograph, Albany, NY] (Box 11, Folder 18)
  Biographical / Historical
  Bassett was superintendent and general freight agent of the Northern Division of the Southern Pacific Railroad.
  Southern Pacific Railroad Company; Bassett, A.C. (Almeron Cornelius), 1837-
- Dr. L.A. Bauer (Box 11, Folder 19)
  Bauer, L. A. (Louis Agricola), 1865-1932
- R.W. Baxter, Central Pacific Railroad [SF Chronicle photograph, notes on verso], 1919 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  Baxter was foreman of Central Pacific's track-laying gang during the construction of the trancontinental railroad. He poses here with the hammer used to drive the golden spike at Promontory Point, Utah as well as the shovel used to turn the first earth in Sacramento.
  Central Pacific Railroad--Construction; Baxter, R. W. (Robert William), 1833-1922
- Delilah L. Beasley [Ramey Studio photograph, Oakland, CA] (Box 11, Folder 21)
  Beasley, Delilah L. (Delilah Leontium), 1871-1934
- August Ferdinand Bebel [J. Baruch photograph, Berlin] (Box 11, Folder 22)
  Barnes/Pacific Slope collection.
  Bebel, August, 1840-1913
- Albert M. Bender [several photographs, including one with Robinson Jeffers & two at the Atherton house of Rosalie Meyer Stern, also pictured] (Box 11, Folder 23)
  From the Albert M. Bender papers, 1871-1948 (M0025): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082743
  Bender, Albert M. (Albert Maurice), 1866-1941; Stern, Rosalie Meyer, 1869-1956; Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962
- Stephen Vincent Benet & unidentified man (Box 11, Folder 24)
  From the Edith R. Mirrielees papers, 1870-1964 (SC1028): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4085110
  Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1827-1895
- Walter Besant [Elliot & Fry photograph, London] (Box 11, Folder 25)
  Besant, Walter, 1836-1901
- John Biddle, American Camp Miner 1850-1910, circa 1901 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  Columbia (Calif.); Miners -- California.; Tuolumne County (Calif.)
- Henry Meade Bland, Poet Laureate of California [2 photographs] (Box 11, Folder 27)
  Bland, Henry Meade, 1863-1931
- William Boggs, Pioneer [Brayton photograph, Napa], about 1901 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  Barnes/Pacific Slope collection. Photograph given by Boggs to Mary Sheldon Barnes with a short note. Boggs was the son of Governor Lilburn Boggs of Missouri; they came to Sonoma, California in 1846.
  The Society of California Pioneers holds the William Montgomery Boggs Papers C058775: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c88g8r56
  Boggs, William Montgomery, 1826-1911
- Bohemian Club [group of 8 men, some of whom may be in other photos. Gabriel Moulin photograph, San Francisco], 1940 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- W.C. Bond (Box 11, Folder 30)
  Bond, William Cranch, 1789-1859
- Homer Bone [inscribed to Ernest Lundeen 1938, stamped as received by U.S. Senator Lundeen on verso] (Box 11, Folder 31)
  Hoover Institute holds the Ernest Lundeen papers, 1860-1944 (50003): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4087887
  Bone, Homer Truett, 1883-1970
- Shadrock Bone [Taber photograph, San Francisco with short biographical note on verso], 1893 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  Possibly Shadrach or Shadrack. Note says "Born on Offren [?] Columbia Street 1869."
- John Wilkes Booth (Box 11, Folder 33)
  Booth, John Wilkes, 1838-1865
- Antoine Borel & Borel Estate [two photos of Borel, several photos of estate 1955] (Box 11, Folder 34)
  San Mateo (Calif.); Borel; Borel, Antoine, 1840-1915
- Tom Brady [biographical notes on verso & enclosed], circa 1860 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  Brother of Matt Brady, pioneer storekeeper in Columbia, California. Photo taken in Ireland (Tom never came to America).
- William Henry Bragg & son William Lawrence Bragg [James Stokley photograph] (Box 11, Folder 36)
  Bragg, William Henry, 1862-1942; Bragg, William Lawrence, Sir, 1890-1971
- Dirk Brouwer [Samuel Kravitt photograph], 1943 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  Brouwer, Dirk, 1902-
- John Casper Branner [Frank Davey photograph, Palo Alto] (Box 11, Folder 38)
  Stanford University Archives holds the John Casper Branner papers, 1882-1921 (SC0034): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4085038
  Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
- G.S. Brett (Box 11, Folder 39)
  Brett, George Sidney, 1879-1944
- Ernest W. Brown [2 photographs] (Box 11, Folder 40)
  Brown, Ernest W. (Ernest William), 1866-1938
- H. Brown [Frank Davey photograph, Palo Alto], 1915 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  Stanford University Archives holds the Harold Chapman Brown papers, 1917-1935 (SCM0406): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/9206582
  Brown, Harold Chapman, 1879-1943
- John Brown [2 CDV photographs, one is a painted portrait] (Box 11, Folder 42)
  Brown, John
- Francis F. Browne [six photographs, one signed 1898, one inscribed to Melville B. Anderson 1911] (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Elizabeth Barrett Browning, Purportedly ["Holly Todd, Copy" on print, probably not Browning] (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Burlingame Family [six photographs of Joel Burlingame, Dewitt Burligame, Susie Burlingame Phillips and others, with envelope to Anson Burlingame 1939] (Box 11, Folder 45)
  See also the Anson Burlingame papers, 1856-1939: https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/5676635 (Part of the Californian and Western Manuscripts Collection)
  Burlingame family
- Peter H. Burnett [Taber photograph, San Francisco] (Box 11, Folder 46)
  Burnett, Peter H. (Peter Hardeman), 1807-1895
- John Burns [Ball photograph, London] (Box 11, Folder 47)
  Burns, John, 1858-1943
- Harry Butler and Wife [William Shew photograph, San Francisco] (Box 11, Folder 48)
- Florian Cajori [2 photographs, one inscribed] (Box 11, Folder 49)
  Cajori, Florian, 1859-1930
- Columbia Home Guards. Joe Smith [possibly Joseph A. Smith, Aid-de-Camp, with rank of Captain], Gen. Dobie [Brigadier General, Third Brigade A.E. Dobbie], Davies [Brigadier General William A. Davies], Capt. Hooker [Captain Ambrose E. Hooker], 1861 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  "Tuolumne Home Guard and was officially mustered in as Company A, First Infantry Battalion, Third Brigade, on September 10, 1861. A. E. Hooker, a resident of Columbia, who was elected as Captain at the first meeting of the Home Guard, was largely responsible for the organization and equipment of the company and to his efforts was due much of their later success ... Reorganized and mustered in as a unit of the National Guard of California under the title Tuolumne Guard, 4 July 1866." http://www.militarymuseum.org/TuolomneHomeGuard.html
  California State Archives holds the Militia Companies Records, 1849-1880: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf0r29n3x1. Tuolumne Home Guard is filed as Item No. B3410-2.
  Columbia (Calif.); Tuolumne County (Calif.); United States -- Militia; California. Militia. Tuolumne Home Guard
- Thomas Carlyle [George Kirchner photograph, New York] (Box 11, Folder 51)
  Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881
- Bliss Carman [2 photographs] (Box 11, Folder 52)
- Casimir-Perier [Ch. Ogerau photograph, Paris], 1894 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  Casimir-Périer, Jean Paul Pierre, 1847-1907
- Cavour [C. Broci photograph, Italy] (Box 11, Folder 54)
  Barnes/Pacific Slope collection
  Cavour, Camillo Benso, conte di, 1810-1861
- Chiang Kai-Shek, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975
- Charlie Chaplin and unidentified [real photo postcard] (Box 11, Folder 56)
  Chaplin, Charlie, 1889-1977
- Prof. Francis James Child (Box 11, Folder 57)
  Child, Francis James, 1825-1896
- Dr. George Chilton [photograph of painting by Charles Loring Elliot, letter enclosed] (Box 11, Folder 58)
  Chilton, George, 1768-1836
- Major L.N. Clayton [brush maker, clipping on verso] (Box 11, Folder 59)
- Samuel Clemens [inscribed to R.L. Wilbur from Cyril Clemens, The Mark Twain Society 1928] (Box 11, Folder 60)
  Twain, Mark, 1835-1910
- Irvin S. Cobb [4 photos with others, probably at 1936 Bohemian Club] (Box 11, Folder 61)
  Cobb, Irvin S. (Irvin Shrewsbury), 1876-1944; Bohemian Club (San Francisco, Calif.)
- Bohemian Grove [2 photographs with unidentified man seated at a table, one with group], 1937 (Box 11, Folder 62)
- General Villa and Mrs. Villa [real photo postcard], 1-1-1914 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  Corral Vda. de Villa, Luz, 1894-1981; Villa, Pancho, 1878-1923
- Frank Condon [inscribed to Sam Blythe 1924] (Box 12, Folder 1)
- [illegible] Cook [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Sam] (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Jay Cooke [signed] (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Cooke, Jay, 1821-1905
- Calvin Coolidge [group photograph] (Box 12, Folder 4)
- George Creel [signed March 1932] (Box 12, Folder 5)
  See also the Hoover Institution's George Creel miscellaneous papers, 1899-1976, https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4087844
  Creel, George, 1876-1953
- Avery H. Cummins [biographical notes on verso, worked for Central Pacific, also a "base-ballist"] (Box 12, Folder 6)
- George William Curtis [2 photographs; one Warren's, Boston, one Purdy & Frear, Ithaca NY] (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Curtis, George William, 1824-1892
- Professor Curtis [name written on verso presumed to be subject] (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Richard Henry Dana [copy print of painting] (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Dana, Richard Henry, Jr., 1815-1882
- Daudet [Nadar photograph, Paris, sold by JG Cupples, Boston] (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Daudet, Alphonse, 1840-1897
- Dr. Termen L. Davis, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Richard Harding Davis [Pach Brothers photograph, New York] (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Davis, Richard Harding, 1864-1916
- R. H. Davis [inscribed to Sam Blythe] (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Lizzie Donegan [Wells photograph, Sonora CA. biographical notes on verso] (Box 12, Folder 14)
  born 1850 at Saw Mill Flat, later married Al [probably Allen McLain] Harkness, horseracing/livery man in Jamestown.
  Tuolumne County (Calif.); Columbia (Calif.)
- Charles Doolittle (Box 12, Folder 15)
  Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
- Jack B. Douglass [biographical notes on verso] (Box 12, Folder 16)
  Owned saloons in Columbia and later Stockton, California. Died 1900.
- R. Doyle [R.A. Lewis photograph, New York] (Box 12, Folder 17)
  Gift of Katherine E. Doyle 9/1/65.
- John T. Doyle [Morse photograph, San Francisco, inscribed to daughter Fannie] (Box 12, Folder 18)
  The California Historical Society holds the John T. Doyle Papers, 1855-1905 (MSD 760): http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3779n5m0
  Doyle, John T. (John Thomas), 1819-1906
- Owen J. Doyle [Wells photograph, Sonora CA. biographical notes on verso] (Box 12, Folder 19)
  Born in New York 1869, was sheriff in Tucson, later a miner, came to Columbia 1920.
- Joseph Dyer [inscribed as Joe Dyer to Sam B. Blythe 1941 on enclosed strip of paper] (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Arthur S. Eddington [signed Elliot & Fry photograph, London] (Box 12, Folder 21)
  Eddington, Arthur Stanley, Sir, 1882-1944
- Dr. Harry Edmund [Bachrach photograph and obituary clipping 1945] (Box 12, Folder 22)
- A. Eigner [biographical notes on verso] (Box 12, Folder 23)
  Russian astronomer & geologist, professor. First name possibly Adolph?
- Emanuel II [sic. does not appear to be King Victor Emmanuel II of Italy] (Box 12, Folder 24)
  Barnes/Pacific Slope Collection
- Ralph Waldo Emerson [signed E. & H.T. Anthony photograph, New York] (Box 12, Folder 25)
  Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882
- B.W. Evermann [2 photographs, one inscribed 1883] (Box 12, Folder 26)
  Once owned by David Starr Jordan, later by Isabel McCracken. Gift of McCracken estate 1/12/56
  Evermann, Barton Warren, 1853-1932
- Colonel Eyre (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Antonio Favaro [with part of envelope from Prof. Favaro to Frederick E. Brasch at Stanford 1916] (Box 12, Folder 28)
  Favaro, Antonio, 1847-1922
- Jules Ferry [Benque photograph, Paris] (Box 12, Folder 29)
  Ferry, Jules, 1832-1893
- Charles K. Field and group [inscribed by Field: "Two Portlanders and the stranger within their gates"] (Box 12, Folder 30)
  Stanford University Archives holds the Charles K. Field collection, 1895-1948 (SC0575) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4329948; Manuscripts holds a Cheerio collection
  Field, Charles K. (Charles Kellogg), 1873-1948
- Cyrus W. Field [2 photographs, one by Taber, San Francisco, one by Rockwood, New York] (Box 12, Folder 31)
  Gift of Mrs. Timothy Hopkins.
  Field, Cyrus W. (Cyrus West), 1819-1892
- P. Fox (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Johanna Finn, Wife of John Finn [Wright's photograph, San Jose. biographical notes on verso] (Box 12, Folder 33)
- Edward Curtis Franklin [Frank Davey photograph, Palo Alto and clipping 1927] (Box 12, Folder 34)
  Franklin, Edward Curtis, 1862-1937
- Sir James George Frazer [copy print of Annan & Sons photograph 1933] (Box 12, Folder 35)
  Frazer, James George, 1854-1941
- John C. Frémont [2 photographs] (Box 12, Folder 36)
  Reese's California Views photograph, Santa Cruz featuring General Frémont and family 1846 is a gift of A.T. Greene. Copy print is gift from Paul P. Parker with note: "This picture of Frémont given to me by W.S. Johnson. He and Frémont were personal friends."
  Frémont, John Charles, 1813-1890; Frémont, Jessie Benton, 1824-1902
- Edwin B. Frost, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  Frost, Edwin Brant, 1866-1935
- Robert Frost [several photographs] (Box 12, Folder 38)
  Robert Frost and Wallace Stegner [Palo Alo Times photo by Gene Tupper]; six 1958 snapshots of Frost by H. Walker Taylor, Jr., one with Stegner; Lesley Frost viewing Robert Frost exhibition in Bender Room 5-3-1974 [Stanford News & Publications Service]
  See also the Robert Frost at Stanford collection, 1936-1958 (SC1229): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10716759
  Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Stegner, Wallace, 1909-1993
- Gambetta [Etienne Carjat photograph, Paris] (Box 12, Folder 39)
  Gambetta, Léon, 1838-1882
- James A. Garfield and family [painted portraits published by Edward Lovejoy, Chicago] (Box 12, Folder 40)
  Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881
- Fred W. Goudy [signed], 1915 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  "Taylor & Taylor Collection" written on verso
- William Gerstle [Van Bosch photograph, Frankfurt, Germany] (Box 12, Folder 42)
  Gerstle, William Lewis, 1868-1947
- Andre Girard (Box 12, Folder 43)
  Girard, André, 1901-1968
- Ulysses S. Grant [2 photographs] (Box 12, Folder 44)
  From the Burlingame Family Photos
  Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885
- Ulysses S. Grant & family [several photos] (Box 12, Folder 45)
  Historical Events & Notable Sayings of the Honored and Lamented U.S. Grant [small round placard by C.D. Mosher, Chicago. Accessioned by Stanford Museum July 20, 1903]; Rockwood photograph, New York [Accessioned by Stanford Museum July 20, 1903]; Charles L. Ritzmann photograph, New York [Accessioned by Stanford Museum July 20, 1903]; General U.S. Grant and Family, at Mt. McGregor 6-19-1885 [Barrett photograph, New York, two slightly different cabinet cards]; Julia D. Grant [signed W. Kurtz photograph, New York]; Julia Cantacuzène Grant [Julia Dent Cantacuzène Spiransky-Grant] [Boissonnas & Eggler photograph, Paris signed St. Petersbourg 1902] Whitehaven...The Dent homestead, Mrs. Grant's Home [painting reproduced as cabinet card]
  Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885; Grant, Julia Dent, 1826-1902; Cantacuzene, Julia, Princess, 1876-1975
- R. Grant [D.M. Filshill photograph] (Box 12, Folder 46)
  Newton collection
- Jules Grevy [Charles Jacotin photograph, Paris] (Box 12, Folder 47)
  Grévy, Jules, 1807-1891
- Robert T. Gunther with Prujean's Astrolabe [Elliott & Fry photograph, London, inscribed 1925] (Box 12, Folder 48)
  Gunther, R. T. (Robert Theodore), 1869-1940
- Edward Everett Hale [Allen & Rowell photograph] (Box 12, Folder 49)
  Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909
- George E. Hale [signed James Stokley photograph, Washington, D.C.], 1929 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  Hale, George Ellery, 1868-1938
- William Frederick Halsey [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Mrs. Ewing] (Box 12, Folder 51)
  Halsey, William F. (William Frederick), 1882-1959
- Cedric Hardwicke [Vandamm photograph, New York] (Box 12, Folder 52)
  Hardwicke, Cedric, 1893-1964
- Gerhart Hauptmann [F. Baruch photograph, Berlin] (Box 12, Folder 53)
  Hauptmann, Gerhart, 1862-1946
- Nathaniel Hawthorne [signed on attached strip of paper] (Box 12, Folder 54)
  Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1804-1864
- Mrs. Hayes. 49er and a wonderful gal. Columbia [Wells photograph, Sonora CA] (Box 12, Folder 55)
- Ernest Hemingway and unidentified [inscribed to Dr. Wilbur] (Box 12, Folder 56)
  Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1960
- Joseph Hergesheimer [inscribed to Martha Ewing Newcome 1922] (Box 12, Folder 57)
  Hergesheimer, Joseph, 1880-1954
- Jose Manual Hernandez [inscribed to James Deitrick 1913] (Box 12, Folder 58)
  From the James Deitrick papers, 1900-1918 (M0140): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082780
  Hernández, José Manuel, 1853?-1921
- Fritz [Kreibs?] [signed 1915] (Box 12, Folder 59)
  Gidt of Harris De Haven Connick, Edythe Russ Connick
- Oliver Wendell Holmes [signed Warren? photograph, Cambridge] (Box 12, Folder 60)
  Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894
- G.J. Holyoake [Elliott & Fry photograph, London] (Box 12, Folder 61)
  Holyoake, George Jacob, 1817-1906
- Theo D. Judah [copy print of Carleton Watkins photograph labeled Popkins, Greenfield, Mass., with printed signature] (Box 12, Folder 62)
  Judah, Theodore D. (Theodore Dehone), 1826-1863; Watkins, Carleton E., 1829-1916
- George Washington Hough 1836-1909 (Box 12, Folder 63)
  Hough, G. W. (George Washington), 1836-1909
- Richard Hovey [3 photographs. One Steffens photograph, Chicago, one possibly with his mother, one panel of three portraits, gift of Brice J. King] (Box 12, Folder 64)
  Hovey, Richard, 1864-1900
- Julia Ward Howe [signed J.E. Purdy photograph, Boston], 1902 (Box 12, Folder 65)
  From the home of Mrs. Max C. Sloss.
  Howe, Julia Ward, 1819-1910
- Kin Hubbard [inscribed to Sam G. Blythe] (Box 12, Folder 66)
  Hubbard, Kin, 1868-1930
- Governor Charles Evans Hughes [5 photographs of Hughes and party touring San Francisco], 1916 (Box 12, Folder 67)
  From the Francis V. Keesling papers, 1906-1957 (M0100): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082770
  Hughes, Charles Evans, 1962-1948
- Kate d'Esterre-Hughes [J.W. Debenhem, Claremont Studio photograph, Surbiton, England] (Box 12, Folder 68)
  Several photographs of a women's automobile club which d'Esterre-Hughes was involved with are filed with the Hopkins Transportation Collection photographs, 1870-1964 (M0234): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082994
  d'Esterre-Hughes, Kate
- Victor Hugo [2 photographs; one J.M. Lopez, one Nadar, both in Paris] (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Sheldon/Pacific Slope collection
  Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885
- Ch. Hermite (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Newton collection.
  Hermite, Charles, 1822-1901
- William Jackson Humphreys [Harris & Ewing photograph with letter to Frederick Brasch at Smithsonian Division of Library of Congress, 1935] (Box 13, Folder 3)
  Humphreys, a US Weather Bureau professor of meteorological physics, had borrowed the Harris & Ewing print from Brasch to make personal copies.
  Humphreys, W. J. (William Jackson), 1862-1949
- Thomas Sterry Hunt (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
- William Irwin [Harris & Ewing photograph inscribed to Martha 1909] (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Irwin, Will, 1873-1948
- Sir James H. Jeans, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Jeans, James, 1877-1946
- Robinson Jeffers [two photographs, one signed by photographer illegibly, one with Albert Bender at Jeffer's "castle" in Carmel Feb.1929] (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962; Bender, Albert M. (Albert Maurice), 1866-1941
- Hiram Johnson [Underwood & Underwood photograph] (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Aksel G.S. Josephson [with wife? biographical information on verso] (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Josephson, Aksel G. S. (Aksel Gustav Salomon), 1860-1944
- Kamehameha IV of Hawaii and family [5 carte de visite photographs] (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Kamehameha IV [H.L. Chase photograph, Honolulu. Kamehameha's name possibly written by Emma]; Queen Emma [M. Dickson photograph, Honolulu; inscribed as Emma Kaleleonalani March 1, 1877]; H.R.H. Prince of Hawaii [Prince Albert Edward Kamehameha, d.1862. Hyman Davis photograph of painting, London. Inscribed to Mr. M.J. Burke (?) by Emma Kaleleonalani March 1, 1877]; two more uncaptioned M. Dickson photographs, Honolulu; one of Queen Emma, other unidentified.
  Kamehameha IV, King of the Hawaiian Islands, 1834-1863; Emma, Queen, consort of Kamehameha IV, King of the Hawaiian Islands, 1836-1885
- Louis C. Karpinski [Rentschlers photograph, Ann Arbor; inscribed to Fred Brasch], 1929 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Karpinski, Louis Charles, 1878-1956
- Sheila Kaye-Smith [two singed photographs, one by Roy Hudson A.R.P.S., England] (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Kaye-Smith, Sheila, 1887-1956
- Francis V. Keesling [6 photographs] (Box 13, Folder 13)
  See also Francis Keesling papers M0100 & M0258
  Atascadero - Joint Regular Army and Narional Guard encampment 1908 [man on horse]; photograph of newspaper comic "This And That About Francis V. Keesling by Denis McCarthy" SF News circa 1930; three group photos with identifications
- Louis Kossuth (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Kossuth, Lajos, 1802-1894
- Jan Kubelik [signed real photo postcard] (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Kubelík, Jan
- Peter B. Kyne [Hartsook photograph with enclosed inscription to Sam Blythe 1930] (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Kyne, Peter B. (Peter Bernard), 1880-1957
- Irving Langmuir [with printed biography] (Box 13, Folder 17)
  Langmuir, Irving, 1881-1957
- William Leary [or Henry?] [inscribed to Sam Blythe] (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Levi Brothers [John A. Todd photograph, Sacramento, with biographical notes on verso], circa 1895 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  Dave, Abe, Louis & Mose Levi were merchants in Columbia, California.
- John L. Lewis [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] president of United Mine Workers (Box 13, Folder 20)
  Lewis, John L. (John Llewellyn), 1880-1969
- [Dr. Wollin Libby?] [Bassano photograph, London] (Box 13, Folder 21)
- [M.S. Niven Lime?] [Harris & Ewing photograph, inscribed 1912] (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Abraham Lincoln [three copy prints and one Miss Gillett photograph, Saline, Michigan, stamped T.S. Oldroyd] (Box 13, Folder 23)
  Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865
- Col. Lindbergh [2 photographs, one signed group photograph by Luis F. Toro, Venezuela, one image with printed signature of Lindbergh standing in front of plane] (Box 13, Folder 24)
- David Livingstone [Maull & Fox photograph, London] (Box 13, Folder 25)
  Livingstone, David, 1813-1873
- Henry Wadsworth Longfellow [2 photographs; one signed Charles Taber, New Bedford, Mass.; one signed 1866] (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Mrs. George Loomis. Aunt of Mrs. Elkins [Gilbert & Bacon photograph, Philadelphia] (Box 13, Folder 27)
- James Russell Lowell [2 photographs; Purdy & Frear photograph, Ithaca NY, one signed Brady photograph, New York] (Box 13, Folder 28)
  Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891
- Macaulay [Brockmann's Collection/Kirchner & Co. photograph of P. Kramer painting] (Box 13, Folder 29)
  Macaulay, Thomas Babington Macaulay, Baron, 1800-1859
- William D. MacMillan [Underwood & Underwood photograph, Chicago] (Box 13, Folder 30)
  MacMillan, W. D. (William Duncan), 1871-1948
- Eugene MacPike [signed 1933] (Box 13, Folder 31)
  McPike, Eugene Fairfield, 1870-1946